In order to calculate the correct price for
オーダーの総額を正しく計算するには
the order summary, we should pass the information
ユーザが どのトッピングを選択したかという情報を
about which toppings the user has selected into the calculatePrice method.
calculatePrice メソッドに伝えます
I'm choosing to do all the heavy lifting and calculation
ここでは手間のかかる全ての処理や計算を
within the calculatePrice method, so it centralizes all of this related logic.
calculatePrice メソッド内で行うことで 関連する全てのロジックを集中化させます
By consolidating everything into this method, if there's a problem with how
このメソッドに全てを一元化させることで 値段の計算に間違いがあった場合
the price is calculated, we can check the code in a single place.
一つの場所でコードを確認できます
It's a lot more manageable.
管理が非常に楽です
Then, within this method,
このメソッド内で
we're going to figure out the base price of one cup of coffee.
一杯のコーヒーの基本価格を決めます
This is just like I showed you earlier.
先にお見せしたのと同じです
If the coffee should have whipped cream, then add a dollar.
ホイップクリームをのせる場合 1ドルプラスします
If the coffee should have chocolate, then add $2.
コーヒーにチョコレートを加える場合 2ドルをプラスします
Then take the base price of one cup of coffee and
それから 一杯分のコーヒーの値段に
multiply it by the quantity ordered to determine the total order price.
オーダー数をかけて オーダーの総額を出します
First let's pass in the information about the whipped cream and
ホイップクリームとチョコレートの チェックボックスに
chocolate check boxes into the calculatePrice method.
関する情報を calculatePrice メソッドに挿入していきましょう
I'm going to pass in the booleans hasWhippedCream and hasChocolate.
プール値に hasWhippedCream と hasChocolate を挿入します
There's no point in passing in the actual CheckBox objects, because all we
実際の チェックボックスの名前を 挿入する必要はありません
care about are these boolean values for calculating the price.
価格計算に必要なのは これらのプール値だけです
Android Studio tells me that there's an error because the method signature
Android Studio で メソッドシグネチャが一致しないという
doesn't match.
エラーが生じています
I'm trying to call a method that has been defined to have
ゼロ入力パラメータを持つことが規定された
zero input parameters.
メソッドを呼び出したいと思います
Let's go down to where the calculatePrice method is being defined.
スクロールダウンし calculatePrice メソッドを規定します
I'm going to change the method signature so
メソッドシグネチャを変更し
that it takes in two input parameters, a boolean called addWhippedCream and
二つのパラメータである addWhippedCream と
a boolean called addChocolate.
addChocolate のプール値を挿入します
You can call these input parameters whatever name you want.
これらの入力パラメータの名前は 好きにつけて構いません
I just chose to use a different name than what was passed in,
名前は一致しなくても良い事をお見せするのに
just to show you that these names don't have to match.
ここでは　挿入時とは違う名前を使っています
I also updated the Javadoc to describe these two new input parameters.
これら二つの新しい入力パラメータを説明するのに Javadoc も更新しました
That way someone calling the method will know what to pass in.
そうすれば メソッドを呼び出した人が 挿入すべき内容を把握できます
Next, within the calculatePrice method I have to do all the logic about changing
次に calculatePrice 内で トッピングに応じて値段を変えるための
the price based on these toppings.
ロジックを調整します
First, I'm going to calculate the base price, so
はじめに 基本価格を計算します
I'm going to create an integer variable called basePrice.
まず basePrice と言う 整数の変数を作成します
I'm going to start the value at 5 because a cup of coffee cost $5.
コーヒー1杯は5ドルなので 値を 5 とします
Then I'm going to create an if statement.
それから If 文を作成します
If the boolean addWhippedCream is true, then the user wants whipped cream.
addWhippedCream というプール値が正しければ ホイップクリームが欲しいということになります
That means we should add $1 onto the base price of one cup of coffee.
つまり コーヒー1杯の基本価格に 1ドルプラスする必要があります
Okay, that should handle the whipped cream case.
これで ホイップクリームに関しては OKですね
Now, let's move onto the chocolate case.
ではチョコレートの場合を見ていきましょう
I'm going to create another if statement.
もう一つ If 文を作成します
I don't need an else block of code, because
else を伴う節は必要ありません
if the user doesn't want whipped cream, I don't have to do anything at all.
ユーザーがホイップクリームを求めない場合は 何もしなくて良いからです
In fact, if I wanted to type an else case, this is what it would look like.
else 節を加えたい場合は このようになります
I would just have a comment that says, do nothing.
「do nothing（何もしない）」 という文を加えるだけです
Android studio is smarter than that, though, and
しかし Android studio は有能で
notices that the else statement has an empty body.
else ステートメントのボックスが 空であることを認識します
Their advice is that this type of code of confusing, and
そして この種のコードは分かりづらく
can be the result of a typo.
タイプミスの結果である可能性を示します
It's also extra lines of code that we don't need, so
それに 必要のない余分な行ですから
let's just erase the else block.
else を含む箇所は削除してしまいます
Now we can move on to the chocolate case.
では チョコレートの場合に移ります
The chocolate topping is completely independent from the whipped cream
チョコレートのトッピングは完全に
topping.
ホイップクリームとは別です
It doesn't matter if the user chooses one or the other,
ユーザーがどちらを選ぶかは 関係ありません
they're not dependent on each another.
互いに独立しているからです
So I'm going to create a separate if case.
ですから 別の If 文を作成します
If the user wants chocolate,
ユーザーがチョコレートを望んだ場合
then we need to modify the base price to be basePrice + 2.
基本価格を 基本価格プラス2にする
Again, we could have an else block of code, but it would do nothing.
ここでも else 文が使えますが 加えたところで違いは出ません
If the user doesn't want chocolate, we don't have to adjust the price at all,
チョコレートが望まれなければ 値段の調整が必要ないというだけです
so let's just delete this code because it's unnecessary.
ですから 必要ないのでコードは削除しましょう
Reading through our code, we have a base price of $5 per cup of coffee.
コードを見ていくと コーヒー1杯の基本価格は5ドル
If the user wants whipped cream, then we need to increase the base price by $1.
ホイップクリームを加える場合は 値段を1ドル上げる
Then if the user wants chocolate,
チョコレートを加える場合は
then we need to increase the base price by $2.
基本価格を2ドル上げるとしました
Then to calculate the total order price,
オーダー価格を計算するには
we need to multiply quantity times the price of one cup of coffee.
一杯のコーヒーの価格にオーダー数をかけます
Okay, this code looks like it should work.
よし　良さそうですね
I also added inline comments above each block of code, so
コードのまとまりの上に それぞれコメントも書いて
that when we come back to this code later, we'll remember what we did.
後で何をしたのか思い出せるようにします
Now, let's run the app to check that it works.
ではアプリで 実際に実行されるか確認しましょう
Okay, let's test the cases that we went over together earlier.
最初にやったのと同じ場合で確認しましょう
If we choose the whipped cream topping and a quantity of 3,
ホイップクリーム入りで 3杯注文したい場合
Then each cup will be $6.
1杯文は6ドルになります
$6 times 3 is $18, and it calculates 18, nice.
6ドルの3倍は18です ちゃんと18と出ました
If I add the chocolate topping, then each cup of coffee will cost $8.
チョコレートのトッピングの場合 コーヒー1杯は8ドルになります
If I have a quantity of 2, then the total price will be $16.
2つオーダーする場合 合計金額は16ドルです
We tried just using a whipped cream topping and we got the correct answer.
ホイップクリームだけつける場合を確認して 正常に機能しましたね
We tried a case with both whipped cream and
ホイップクリームとチョコレート
chocolate topping, and we got the right answer.
両方をトッピングする場合も試し 正常に機能しました
Now let's try just choosing the chocolate topping.
チョコレートだけの場合もやってみましょう
I'll change the quantity to 1, and then hit Order.
オーダーの数を1にして 「Order」ボタンを押します
This looks correct, because we have $5 for one cup of coffee plus $2 for
コーヒー一杯は5ドルで チョコレートのトッピングが2ドルなので
chocolate, and that brings us to $7.
7ドル 正しいですね
If I change this to 4, then the total updates, assuming $7 per cup of coffee.
オーダー数を4とすると コーヒー1杯を7ドルとしてその合計が出ます
Awesome.
ばっちり
It looks like it works.
ちゃんと機能しています
I ran through those test cases pretty quickly.
以上 急ぎ足で確認しましたが
What I was trying to do,
大切なことは
though, is make sure that all the possible code paths were run through.
考えられる限りのコードパスが 正常に実行するかを確認するという点です
For example, if we run the app, and we never select the whipped cream check
例えば アプリの実行でホイップクリームの ボックスにチェックすることがないと
box, then we would never test whether this code in here works.
ここのコードがいかに機能するかを 確かめることができません
So we need to pick conditions that will cause all parts of our code to execute.
ですから コードの全てが実行されるように 条件を設定し確認する必要があります
So we selected the whipped cream topping and we also selected the chocolate
先ほど ホイップクリームをつけた場合と チョコレートをつけた場合
topping to make sure that this code also executed.
両方試して ここのコードの実行を確認しました
To be even more thorough we should test for
更には これら二つの
all the combinations of these two boolean variables.
プール変数の組み合わせを全て 実行して確認することが望まれます
All these combinations will result in different behavior in this method, so
これらの組み合わせは全て メソッド内で異なる動作をもたらします
we want to make sure that our code works in all those cases.
全ての場合にコードが正常に実行することを 確認してください
Since the base price is being calculated as we go along, we can also
こうして 基本価格が設定されていますので
use log messages to make sure that it's being calculated as expected.
思い通り計算が実行されているか確認するため ログメッセージを使うこともできます
Anyways, these are just things to keep in mind as you write code that gets more
以上 フロー制御ステートメントを使って より複雑なコードを書く際に
complex with these control flow statements.
気をつけるべきことをご紹介しました